<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<chapter id="overview">
   <title>BPMN Convert Overview</title>
    <para>This chapter gives you a short overview of JBoss BPMN Convert module.</para>
    <para>JBoss BPMN Convert module is a tool used for a BPMN file translation.</para>
    <para>As a part of JBoss tools, JBoss BPMN Convert module implements BPMN -> JPDL translation. You can get a basic JPDL file from a BPMN file by using this module.</para>
    <para>The BPMN file may be written by hands or with the help of some editors. In this guide, we use STP BPMN editor to draw a BPMN file.</para> 
    <para>You can download the editor which is included into  BPMN Modeler from Eclipse download or update site. On the <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/bpmn">Eclipse BPMN project page</ulink> you can find the necessary links and other related information.</para>  
  
<section>
    <title>Key Features of JBoss BPMN Convert module</title>
    <para>For a start, we propose you to look through the table of main features of JBoss BPMN Convert module:</para>

    <table>
        
        <title>Key Functionality of JBoss BPMN Convert module</title>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            
            <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
            <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
            <colspec colnum="3" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
            
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry>Feature</entry>
                    <entry>Benefit</entry>
                    <entry>Chapter</entry>
                </row>
            </thead>
            
            <tbody>
                
                <row>
                    <entry><para>STP BPMN Editor</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBoss BPMN Convert module contains STP Business Process Modeling Notation (BPMN) Editor which is a tool to express any processes in a graphical form (simple diagrams with a set of some graphical elements). Created BPMN files can then be converted to jPDL.</para></entry>
                    <entry>
                        <link linkend="createbpmnfile">creating a BPMN file by STP BPMN editor</link>
                    </entry>
                </row>
                
                
            </tbody>
            
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
    

</section>
    
    
</chapter>