<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="Introduction" xreflabel="Introduction">
 <?dbhtml filename="TargetAudience.html"?>
  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>jBPM</keyword>
      <keyword>Target</keyword>
      <keyword>developers</keyword>
      <keyword>Audience</keyword>
     </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>
 <title>Introduction</title>
  <para>All developers and process analysts who are beginning to use JBoss jBPM should read this Getting Started guide. It will give them a jumpstart showing how to create a process definition.</para>
  <section id="Preface">
<?dbhtml filename="Preface.html"?>
<title>Preface</title>
<para>This document introduces the use of the JBoss jBPM Graphical Process Designer (GPD) to create workflow processes. It will help first time users with the following tasks :</para>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>Install the JBoss jBPM GPD Eclipse plugin available from the JBoss jBPM download area</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Set up a Java project in Eclipse and prepare it to do test driven process development</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Using the creation wizard to create an empty process definition</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Use the designer palette to draw the first processdefinition</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Show how the xml processdefinition can be inspected as an xml file</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Set up a Java project in Eclipse and prepare it to do test driven process development</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Write an example process test case</para></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>If you have questions, please feel free to contact Koen Aers or Tom Baeyens for more information.</para>
  </section>
 
 <section id="feature_list">
  
  <title>Feature list</title>
  
  
  
 <para> JBoss jBPM is a workflow that enable creating and 
  automatization business processes. Look at the list of features below.
  </para>
  <table>
   <title>Key Functionality for JBoss jBPM</title>
   <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
     <row>
      <entry>Feature</entry>
      <entry>Benefit</entry>
     </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
     
     <row>
      <entry>jBDL support</entry>
      <entry>Enable managing workflow processes as well as human tasks and interactions between them. 
       jBDL combines the best both Java and declarative process techniques. Look <link linkend="minimal_process_definition">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Support of Graphical Process Designer (GPD)</entry>
      <entry>For simplifying declarative process development and visualizations of all actions. Look <link linkend="GuidedTourJBossjBPMGPD">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Project Creation wizard</entry>
      <entry>Allows to create a new jBPM template project that already includes all advanced artifacts and core jBPM libraries.
       Look <link linkend="CreatingjBPMProject">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Rich  palette of pre-build process nodes</entry>
      <entry>Provides process-building functionality and gives opportunity even non-programmers to develop processes.
       Look <link linkend="minimal_process_definition">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Support of XML code view</entry>
      <entry>Corresponding XML is generated automatically in the Source view of the process definition editor
       when developing the process. Look <link linkend="the_source_view">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Properties view</entry>
      <entry>Facilitates configuring and editing of all nodes properties. Look <link linkend="the_properties_view">here.</link></entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Interaction with all of the J2EE based integration technologies including Web Services, Java Messaging, 
       J2EE Connectors, JBDC, EJBs.</entry>
      <entry>Enables implementation, provides better functionality and flexibility</entry>
     </row>
     
     <row>
      <entry>Integration with jBoss Seam</entry>
      <entry>Allows to write applications with complex workflows and provides easier interactions between them</entry>
     </row>
     
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
 </section>
 
</chapter>
