<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="Introduction">
	<?dbhtml filename="TargetAudience.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>jBPM</keyword>
			<keyword>Target</keyword>
			<keyword>developers</keyword>
			<keyword>Audience</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>
		This guide demonstrates the use of JBoss jBPM in the creation of a process definition. 
	</para>
	<section id="Preface">
		<?dbhtml filename="Preface.html"?>
		<title>Preface</title>
		<para>
			This document introduces the JBoss jBPM Graphical Process Designer (GPD), which is used to create workflow processes. It will help first time users with the following tasks:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Installing the JBoss jBPM GPD Eclipse plugin, which is available from the JBoss jBPM download area</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Setting up a Java project in Eclipse and preparing it for test driven process development</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Using the creation wizard to create an empty process definition</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Using the designer palette to draw the first process definition</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Demonstrating how the XML process definition can be inspected as an XML file</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Writing an example process test case</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			If you have any questions, please feel free to contact <ulink url="mailto:koen.aers@jboss.com">Koen Aers</ulink> or <ulink url="mailto:tom.baeyens@jboss.com">Tom Baeyens</ulink> for more information.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="feature_list">

		<title>Feature list</title>

		<para> 
			JBoss jBPM is a workflow that enables the creation and automation business processes. The table below lists the main features of JBoss jBPM.
		</para>
		<table>
			<title>Key Functionality for JBoss jBPM</title>
			<tgroup cols="2">
				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Feature</entry>
						<entry>Benefit</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>
				<tbody>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="minimal_process_definition"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Enables the management of workflow processes as well as human tasks and the interactions between them. jPDL combines the best techniques both in Java and in declarative processes.
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="GuidedTourJBossjBPMGPD"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>Is used to simplify declarative process development and the visualization of all actions.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="CreatingjBPMProject"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>Allows the creation of a new jBPM template project that already includes all the advanced artifacts and core jBPM libraries.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="minimal_process_definition"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>Provides process-building functionality and allows non-programmers to develop processes.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="the_views"/>
						</entry>
						<entry></entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="source_mode"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							Shows the corresponding XML that is generated automatically in the Source view of the process definition editor when developing the process.
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="the_properties_view"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>Facilitates configuring and editing of all nodes properties.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="jbpm_gpd_editor"/>
						</entry>
						<entry>The plugin is used for designing the workflow.</entry>
					</row>


					<row>
						<entry>
							Interaction with all of the J2EE based integration technologies including Web Services, Java Messaging, J2EE Connectors, JBDC, EJBs.
						</entry>
						<entry>Enables implementation, provides better functionality and flexibility.</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>Integration with jBoss Seam</entry>
						<entry>Allows applications to be written with complex workflows and provides easier interactions between them.</entry>
					</row>

				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Other relevant resources on the topic</title>
		<para>
			You can find JBoss Developer Studio and JBoss Tools release documentation at <ulink url="http://docs.jboss.org/tools/">http://docs.jboss.org/tools</ulink> in the corresponding release directory.
		</para>
		<para>Additional information can be found in the <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/JBPMWiki">JBoss Wiki</ulink>.</para>
		<para>
			The latest documentation builds are available at <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/">http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs</ulink>.
		</para>
	</section>

</chapter>
