<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="Introduction" xreflabel="Introduction">
 <?dbhtml filename="TargetAudience.html"?>
 <chapterinfo>
  <keywordset>
   <keyword>jBPM</keyword>
   <keyword>Target</keyword>
   <keyword>developers</keyword>
   <keyword>Audience</keyword>
  </keywordset>
 </chapterinfo>
 <title>Introduction</title>
 <para>All developers and process analysts who are beginning to use JBoss jBPM should read this
  Getting Started guide. It will give them a jumpstart showing how to create a process definition.</para>
 <section id="Preface">
  <?dbhtml filename="Preface.html"?>
  <title>Preface</title>
  <para>This document introduces the use of the JBoss jBPM Graphical Process Designer (GPD) to
   create workflow processes. It will help first time users with the following tasks :</para>
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>Install the JBoss jBPM GPD Eclipse plugin available from the JBoss jBPM download
    area</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Set up a Java project in Eclipse and prepare it to do test driven process
    development</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Using the creation wizard to create an empty process definition</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Use the designer palette to draw the first processdefinition</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Show how the xml processdefinition can be inspected as an xml file</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Set up a Java project in Eclipse and prepare it to do test driven process
    development</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Write an example process test case</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>If you have questions, please feel free to contact <ulink url="mailto:koen.aers@jboss.com"
    >Koen Aers</ulink> or <ulink url="mailto:tom.baeyens@jboss.com">Tom Baeyens</ulink> for more
   information.</para>
 </section>

 <section id="feature_list">

  <title>Feature list</title>

  <para> JBoss jBPM is a workflow that enables creating and automatization business processes. Look
   at the list of features below to understand its main functionality.</para>
  <table>
   <title>Key Functionality for JBoss jBPM</title>
   <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
     <row>
      <entry>Feature</entry>
      <entry>Benefit</entry>
     </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="minimal_process_definition">jBDL support</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Enables managing workflow processes as well as human tasks and interactions between
       them. jBDL combines the best both Java and declarative process techniques.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="GuidedTourJBossjBPMGPD">Support of Graphical Process Designer (GPD)</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Is used for simplifying declarative process development and visualizations of all
       actions.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="CreatingjBPMProject">Project Creation wizard</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Allows to create a new jBPM template project that already includes all advanced
       artifacts and core jBPM libraries.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="minimal_process_definition">Rich palette of pre-build process nodes</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Provides process-building functionality and gives opportunity even non-programmers to
       develop processes.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="the_views">A large range of special views, including:</link>
      </entry>
      <entry></entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="source_mode">Support of XML code view</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Shows the corresponding XML that&apos;s generated automatically in the Source view
       of the process definition editor when developing the process.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="the_properties_view">Properties view</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>Facilitates configuring and editing of all nodes properties.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>
       <link linkend="jbpm_gpd_editor">The jBPM Graphical Process Designer editor</link>
      </entry>
      <entry>The plugin is used for designing the workflow.</entry>
     </row>
     

     <row>
      <entry>Interaction with all of the J2EE based integration technologies including Web Services,
       Java Messaging, J2EE Connectors, JBDC, EJBs.</entry>
      <entry>Enables implementation, provides better functionality and flexibility.</entry>
     </row>

     <row>
      <entry>Integration with jBoss Seam</entry>
      <entry>Allows to write applications with complex workflows and provides easier interactions
       between them.</entry>
     </row>

    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
 </section>
 
 <section>
  <title>Other relevant resources on the topic</title>
  <para>All JBoss Developer Studio/JBoss Tools release documentation you can find at<ulink url="http://docs.jboss.org/tools/">http://docs.jboss.org/tools</ulink> in the corresponding release directory.</para>
  <para>There is some extra information on <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/JBPMWiki">JBoss Wiki. </ulink></para>
  <para>The latest documentation builds are available at <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/">http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs</ulink>.</para>
 </section>

</chapter>
