<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="Quick_Howto_Guide" xreflabel="Quick_Howto_Guide">
    <?dbhtml filename="Quick_Howto_Guide.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>jBPM</keyword>
            <keyword/>
            <keyword/>
            <keyword/>
            <keyword/>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>
    <title>Quick Howto Guide</title>

    <para>This chapter contains additional information related to the <property>JBoss
        jBPM</property>.</para>

    <section id="change_core_jbpm_inst">
        <title>Change the Default Core jBPM Installation</title>

        <para> You can change the default <property>jBPM</property> installation by means of the
            Eclipse preference mechanism. Open the Preferences dialog by selecting <emphasis>
                <property>Window &gt; Preferences</property>
            </emphasis> and select the <emphasis>
                <property>JBoss jBPM &gt; Runtime Location</property>
            </emphasis> category. Using this page you can add multiple <property>jBPM</property>
            installation locations and change the default one. The default installation is used for
            the classpath settings when creating a new Process Project. Changing the preferences has
            no influence on already created projects. Getting rid of a <property>jBPM</property>
            installation that&apos;s being referenced by a project however will cause the
            classpath to contain errors. </para>


        <figure>
            <title>The jBPM Preferences Page</title>

            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
        <title>Configuring Task Nodes</title>

        <para>Here, we&apos;ll examine how you can configure the Task nodes in jBPM jPDL GPD.</para>

        <para> You can add Tasks to Task nodes and then configure them in a similar manner as the
            Action configuration mechanism. Let&apos;s consider the process definition similar
            to the previous one that contains three nodes: Start state, Task node and End state. The
            <property>Properties view</property> for selected Task node includes several tabs. </para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Properties View of the selected Task Node</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_2.png"
                        scale="75"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>We should choose the Task tab and then bring up the context menu or click the button
            in the top right corner of the view to add a Task to our Task node.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>Adding a Task to the Task Node</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_3.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Every added Task has its own configuration possibilities. You can access them through
            the <property>Properties view</property> as well.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Task properties</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_4.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>The <property>General page</property> is a place where you can specify the name of a
            Task and its description. For instance, let it be <emphasis>
                <property>approve oder</property>
            </emphasis> with appropriate description that you can see in the figure below.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Task General Page</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_5.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>Now, look at <property>Details page</property>. First, you should specify the due date
            that is a mandatory property for the Task. The due date is the date on which the task
            should be accomplished. Here you can also set a Task priority as well as signalling,
            notifying or blocking. The <emphasis>
                <property>Blocking</property>
            </emphasis> attribute indicates that the process will not be able to continue if this
            task is still unaccomplished. The <emphasis>
                <property>Generate Form...</property>
            </emphasis> button is for creating a simple task form that can be rendered by the jBPM
            console.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Task Details Page</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_6.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>For our example, we specify the due date as 2 business days, choose the high priority
            and also check the <emphasis>
                <property>Signalling</property>
            </emphasis> and <emphasis>
                <property>Notify</property>
            </emphasis> attributes. It means that the Task should be accomplished in 2 business days
            and the assignee will be notified by email when the task is assigned. To specify how the
            Task should be assigned switch on to the <property>Assignment page</property>.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Task Assignment Page</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_7.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>On the <property>Reminder page</property> you can specify whether the assignee will be reminded of the task
            that awaits him.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Task Reminder Page</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_8.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>In our case, the assignee will be reminded by email after two business hours and
            continue to get reminding every business hour after that.</para>
        <para>In the next figure you can see our configuring generated into XML.</para>
        <figure>
            <title>The Task Reminder Page</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Quick_Howto_Guide/quick_howto_guide_9.png"
                        scale="80"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>We hope, our guide will help you to get started with the jPDL process language and jBPM
            workflow on the whole. Besides, for additional information you are welcome on <ulink
                url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=201">JBoss forum</ulink>.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
