<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="the_views" xreflabel="the_views">
    <?dbhtml filename="the_views.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>jBPM</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>

    <title>The views</title>

    <para>Here, it will be explained how to work with views and editors provided by JBDS.</para>
    <para>The views are used for representation and navigation the resources you are working on at
        the moment. One of the advantages of all the views is that all modifications made in the
        current active file are immediately displayed in them. Let’s get acquainted more closely
        with those that the <property>jPDL perspective</property> provides. </para>

    <figure>
        <title>The jPDL Perspective Views and Editors</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_0.png" scale="80"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>

    <para>As you can see in the picture above, the <property>jPDL perspective</property> contains a
        complete set of functionality that&apos;s necessary for working on the jBPM project.</para>

    <section id="the_outline_view">
        <?dbhtml filename="the_outline_view.html"?>
        <title>The Outline View</title>
        <para>To have a way to quickly see an outline of the process use the <emphasis>
                <property>Outline view</property>
            </emphasis> that is presented as the classical tree. If it is not visible select <emphasis>
                <property>Window &gt; Show view &gt; Outline</property>. </emphasis></para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Overview View</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    </section>

    <section id="the_overview">
        <?dbhtml filename="the_outline_view.html"?>
        <title>The Overview</title>
        <para>The main advantage of this view is that it gives visual representation of the whole
            current developing process. Besides, the <emphasis>
                <property>Overview</property>
            </emphasis> comes as a scrollable thumbnail which enables a better navigation of the
            process structure if it&apos;s too large.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Overview</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_2.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    </section>

    <section id="the_properties_view">
        <?dbhtml filename="the_properties_view.html"?>
        <title>The Properties View</title>
        <para> Here, we dwell on the JBDS <property>Properties view</property>.</para>
        <para>Notice if it&apos;s not visible you can access it by navigating <emphasis>
                <property>Window &gt; Show view &gt; Properties</property>. </emphasis></para>
        <para>The view shows the relevant properties of the selected item in the tabbed form. Every
            item has its own set of properties, which can be directly editable in the Properties
            view or by brining up the context menu.</para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Properties View of selected Transition</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_3.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>For example, on the picture above the Properties view displays all the properties for
            a selected transition. Its name has been changed to <emphasis>
                <property>to_auction</property>. </emphasis> We&apos;ve done it directly in
            active General tab of the view. The same way let&apos;s change the name for the
            second transition to <emphasis>
                <property>to_end</property>. </emphasis></para>
        <para>If no one item is selected, the view represents the properties of the whole process
            definition. </para>

        <figure>
            <title>The Properties View of Process Definition</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_4.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

        <para>In this case, it contains six tabs. The first one is the <emphasis>
                <property>General</property>.</emphasis> It allows to specify a process name and add
            necessary description. To illustrate let&apos;s change the process definition name
            to <emphasis>
                <property>jbay</property>. </emphasis></para>
    </section>

    <section id="jbpm_gpd_editor">
        <?dbhtml filename="direct_editing.html"?>
        <title>The jBPM Graphical Process Designer editor.</title>
        <para>The <property>jBPM GPD editor</property> includes four modes: Diagram, Deployment,
            Design and Source, which are available as switchable tabs at the bottom of the editor.
            Let&apos;s dwell on each of them.</para>

        <section id="the_diagram_mode">
            <title>The Diagram mode</title>
            <para> In this mode we define the process in the form of a diagram by means of tools
                provided on the left-hand side of the jBPM GPD. </para>

            <figure>
                <title>The Diagram mode</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_5.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>Besides, some properties can be directly edited in the <property>Diagram
                mode</property> of the graphical editor. One example of this is the <emphasis>
                    <property>name</property>
                </emphasis> property of nodes. You can edit this directly by selecting the node of
                which you want to change the name and then click once inside this node. This enables
                an editor in the node. We change the name of the node to <emphasis>
                    <property>auction</property>. </emphasis></para>
        </section>

        <section id="source_mode">
            <?dbhtml filename="the_source_view.html"?>
            <title>The Source Mode</title>
            <para>Now, that we have defined a simple process definition, we can have a look at the
                XML that is being generated under the covers. To see this XML click on the Source
                tab of the graphical process designer editor.</para>

            <figure>
                <title>The Source Mode</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_6.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The <property>Source mode</property> enables to easily manipulate our XML. That is
                manually inserting and editing necessary elements or attributes. In addition, here
                you can take advantage of content assist.</para>
        </section>

        <section id="design_mode">
            <?dbhtml filename="the_design_view.html"?>
            <title>The Design Mode</title>
            <para>One more way to edit your file is to use <property>Design mode</property>. You can
                see it in the next picture:</para>
            <figure>
                <title>The Design Mode</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_7.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>As you can see above, this mode looks like a table in the first column of which
                the process structure is performed. Here, you can also insert, remove and edit
                elements or attributes, moreover add comments and instructions. Their values can be
                directly edited in the second column of the Design mode table.</para>
            <para>For instance, let’s add a comment on the second transition. For that, you should
                bring up the context menu for it and choose <emphasis>
                    <property>Add Before > Comment</property>. </emphasis></para>

            <figure>
                <title>Adding a Comment</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_8.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>Then, we can put the text <emphasis>This transition leads to the end
                state</emphasis> in the right column as its value.</para>

            <figure>
                <title>Comment is added</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_9.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

        </section>

        <section id="deployment_mode">
            <?dbhtml filename="the_deployment_view.html"?>
            <title>The Deployment Mode</title>
            <para>Finally, to adjust the deployment settings of the project you should switch on to
                the tab that opens the <property>Deployment mode</property>. On the picture below
                the <property>Deployment mode</property> is performed with default settings. Here,
                you can easily modify them or, if the settings won&apos;t match your needs, to
                reset defaults. </para>
            <figure>
                <title>The Deployment Mode</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/the_views/the_views_10.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>

            <para>The button <emphasis>
                    <property>Test Connections</property>
                </emphasis> is necessary to make sure whether all your settings are valid before
                deploying the process.</para>
            <para>Now that we&apos;ve seen how to work with <property>jPDL
                perspective</property>, let's pass on to the project testing.</para>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
